Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572 | Los Angeles, CA 90230

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-phd-1b197986 | GitHub: github.com/Koldenblue

Portfolio: https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a Ph.D. in chemistry and education in full-stack development, both from the University of California Los Angeles (UCLA). Experienced independent researcher, business manager, scientist, and problem solver. Values include community, ethics, integrity, and business sense. Leadership, teamwork, and public speaking skills stem from years spent as a classroom teacher and a group fitness leader. Top aim is to find success in life and improve the lives of others through program design and social interaction.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript/HTML/CSS used as main coding languages
- Emphasis on MERN stack technologies (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js)
- Python as secondary language, with ability and skill to learn further languages
- Use of established libraries such as Redux, jQuery, Flask, Sass, Bootstrap, TypeScript, Material-UI
- SQL database work, through MySQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, and Sequelize
- Non-relational database management using MongoDB, or alternatively Firebase
- Coding techniques include object-oriented programming, asynchronous function handling, mobileresponsive web design, version control with Git, code testing with tools such as Postman and Jest
- AJAX calls for integrating APIs
- Skill in researching programming languages and techniques for example, Python, basic PHP, and basic C/C++ programming accomplished through self-study and professional certification

SAMPLE PROJECTS

• Full portfolio located at https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com

Color Rippler | https://bit.ly/color-rippler-github | https://bit.ly/color-rippler

- Code that renders up to thousands of interactive components in the DOM, using React
- Combines frontend design with JavaScript algorithms. MERN stack is used for data storage, user authentication, and back-end routing.

Express Bartender | https://bit.ly/express-bartender-github | https://bit.ly/express-bartender

- Executed lead back-end scripting for a small team of coders. Led back-end database and routing design. Programmed storage and updates of user information with SQL database.
- Consistently offered help to teammates to solve code difficulties, reviewed team code on GitHub, and contributed overall website design.
- Programmed SQL database of drink recipes acquired through AJAX calls to APIs.

EMPLOYMENT

Aim-Hi Global, LLC. | https://aimhiglobal.com

December 2020 - Current

Web Development Intern

- Led onboarding of a new development team, performing team management duties such as code review, organization, documentation, and website deployment
- Implemented user settings features, added protected route functionality, refactored code, designed calendar frontend, fixed bugs, and improved documentation while working with React and Firebase
- Collaborated on ongoing programming of use of social media APIs such as Facebook and Twitter

Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - Current

- Worked independently on Python timesheet and balance sheet programs, streamlining workflow
- Rigorous documentation of construction projects and account tracking benefitted bottom line
- Managed over a dozen buildings and contributed to purchasing decisions for properties worth millions
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth

Praxair:

Lab Technician and Analytical Scientist

October 2014 - February 2015

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - December 2014

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award and two separate fellowships
- Close supervision of hundreds of undergraduate students in both labs and discussion sections, during teaching of over a dozen college-level chemistry discussion courses

EDUCATION

Computer Science Associate Degree - Santa Monica Community College CS50 Computer Science Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online Full-Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles B.S., Chemistry - University of California, Irvine

In Progress